

DR STUART MILLAR

Phone: +64 22 474 7377

Website: stuart.icu.nz

Personal Statement

I am specialising in Anaesthesia and Intensive Care Medicine. Long term I would like to continue working in both of these areas. I am interested in teaching and the impact of communication on patient care.

I aim to gain further skills in echocardiography and at present I am working towards a Certificate in Clinical Performed Ultrasound (Rapid Cardiac Echocardiography) from the Australasian Society for Ultrasound in Medicine.

Education

Postgraduate Diploma in Child Health (DCH), University of Otago.	2006
Bachelor of Medicine and Bachelor of Surgery (MBChB), University of Otago.	2004

Awards Received

Otago University Scholarship in Medicine, University of Otago.	2001
Agnes Randall Memorial Prize in Physics, University of Otago.	1999

Professional Affiliations

Australian and New Zealand College of Anaesthetists (ANZCA) - Provisional Fellow

Fellowship Examination	Completed – May 2014
Primary Examination	Completed – Sep 2011

College of Intensive Care Medicine (CICM)

Advanced Trainee

Australian and New Zealand Intensive Care Society (ANZICS) - Trainee Membership

Experience

In	tensive Care Senior Registrar, Wellington, New Zealand.	Dec 2014 - Present		
	Wellington Hospital, Wellington, New Zealand.			
Anaesthetic Registrar – Northern Rotational Training Scheme, New Zealand. Jun 2010 – Dec 2014				
	ICU – Middlemore Hospital.	Jun 2014 – Dec 2014		
•	Anaesthesia – Middlemore Hospital.	Dec 2013 – Jun 2014		
•	Paediatric Anaesthesia – Starship Hospital.	Aug 2013 – Dec 2013		
-	Obstetric/Gynaecology Anaesthesia - Level 9, Auckland Hospital.	Apr 2013 – Aug 2013		
	ICU - Cardiothoracic/Vascular ICU, Auckland Hospital.	Dec 2012 – Apr 2013		

■ Cardiothoracic Anaesthesia – Level 4, Auckland Hospital.	Aug 2012 – Dec 2012
■ Anaesthesia – Level 8, Auckland Hospital.	Dec 2011 – Aug 2012
■ Paediatric Anaesthesia – Starship Hospital.	Aug 2011 – Dec 2011
■ Anaesthesia – Level 8, Auckland Hospital.	Apr 2011 – Dec 2011
■ Obstetric/Gynaecology Anaesthesia – Level 9, Auckland Hospital	Dec 2010 – Apr 2011
■ Anaesthesia – North Shore Hospital.	Jun 2010 – Dec 2010
Anaesthetic Senior House Officer, Ireland.	Jan 2009 – Dec 2009
■ Adelaide Meath and National Childrens Hospital, Dublin, Republic of Ireland.	
Medical Registrar, Queensland, Australia.	Aug 2008 – Dec 2008
■ Mackay Base Hospital, Mackay, Queensland, Australia.	
Anaesthetic Senior House Officer, Ireland.	Jan 2008 – Jun 2008
■ Mid Western Regional Hospital, Limerick, Republic of Ireland.	
Career Medical Officer, New South Wales, Australia.	Nov 2006 – Dec 2007
■ ICU – Port Macquarie Base Hospital.	Jul 2007 – Dec 2007
■ Emergency Medicine – Port Macquarie Base Hospital.	Jun 2007 – Jul 2007
■ Emergency Medicine – Coffs Harbour Base Hospital.	Nov 2006 – May 2007
	In 2006 Nov. 2006
Locum House Officer, New Zealand.	Jul 2006 – Nov 2006
Locum House Officer, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand. Courses	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course]	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. House Officer, PGY 1, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ. Advanced Life Support, NZRC. Middlemore Hospital, Auckland, NZ.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ. Advanced Life Support, NZRC. Middlemore Hospital, Auckland, NZ. Emergency Management of Anaesthetic Crises (EMAC). University of Auckland Simulation Centre, N	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014 NZ. Oct 2013
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ. Advanced Life Support, NZRC. Middlemore Hospital, Auckland, NZ. Emergency Management of Anaesthetic Crises (EMAC). University of Auckland Simulation Centre, N. Emergency Ultrasound Course. Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney, Australia.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014 NZ. Oct 2013 Oct 2007
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ. Advanced Life Support, NZRC. Middlemore Hospital, Auckland, NZ. Emergency Management of Anaesthetic Crises (EMAC). University of Auckland Simulation Centre, N. Emergency Ultrasound Course. Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney, Australia. Advanced Paediatric Life Support (APLS). Wellington, NZ.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014 NZ. Oct 2013 Oct 2007 May 2006
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ. Advanced Life Support, NZRC. Middlemore Hospital, Auckland, NZ. Emergency Management of Anaesthetic Crises (EMAC). University of Auckland Simulation Centre, N. Emergency Ultrasound Course. Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney, Australia. Advanced Paediatric Life Support (APLS). Wellington, NZ.	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014 NZ. Oct 2013 Oct 2007 May 2006
House Officer, PGY 2, New Zealand. Courses RACEPlus Echocardiography Course, Nepean Hospital, Sydney. [Upcoming Course] CICM Communication Course, Auckland, NZ. Beyond Basic: Mechanical Ventilation, Hawkes Bay, NZ. Advanced Life Support, NZRC. Middlemore Hospital, Auckland, NZ. Emergency Management of Anaesthetic Crises (EMAC). University of Auckland Simulation Centre, N Emergency Ultrasound Course. Royal North Shore Hospital, Sydney, Australia. Advanced Paediatric Life Support (APLS). Wellington, NZ. Teaching Clinical Lecturer, FANZCA Part 2 Examination Course (Multi-Systems Examination), Wellington	Dec 2005 – Jun 2006 Dec 2004 – Dec 2005 May 2015 Mar 2015 Mar 2015 Jun 2014 NZ. Oct 2013 Oct 2007 May 2006

Feb 2006

Presentations and Audit

Inflammatory Bowel Disease. Case Presentation.

Grand Round				
•	Therapeutic Temperature Management post Cardiac Arrest, Middlemore Hospital, NZ.	Sep 2014		
Lit	rerature Review			
•	NSAID Considerations in Obstetric and Gynaecology Patients.	Aug 2013		
Au	Audit			
•	Venous thromboembolism Audit. Port Macquarie Base Hospital, NSW, Australia.	Oct 2007		
•	Medication Charting Audit. Masterton Hospital, NZ.	Aug 2005		
Pr	resentations (Local and Departmental)			
•	Results of ISAT trial, 18 year followup. Journal Review.	Feb 2015		
•	Lignocaine in Spinal Surgery. Journal Review.	Oct 2013		
•	POISE Trial and Morbidity. Journal Review.	Aug 2013		
•	Transcatheter Aortic Valve Implantation. Journal Review.	Feb 2013		
•	Early Warning Score, Background and Evidence.	Jul 2012		
•	IV Lignocaine infusions for intraoperative and postoperative analgesia.	Mar 2012		
•	Emergence Delirium.	Nov 2011		
•	Oxycodone Analgesia following Total Hip Joint Replacement. Journal Review.	Sep 2011		
•	Intrapartum Fetal Monitoring.	Mar 2011		
•	Blood Transfusion and Jehovah's Witnesses.	Nov 2010		
•	Transurethral Prostatic Resection.	Jul 2009		
•	Multiple Trauma. Case Presentation.	Feb 2008		
•	Mastoiditis. Case Presentation.	May 2006		